one of the things we also should discuss
is the terminology confusion about the
auto for the processors and how we name
different parts of them we have been
calling the stages of the execution
issue was when we obtained the
reservation station in the aerobie entry
dispatch was when the instruction was
selected for execution and commit was
when the instruction has committed this
terminology was introduced in the
original tomasulo's algorithm and then
commit was introduced in the first paper
they talked about arabes so most of the
academics are going to use this
terminology so most of the research
papers that are written will use
something similar to this however some
companies and some of the papers will
for issue use the term not only issue
but also allocate because this is when
we allocate resources for the
instructions so pretty much we allocate
an reservation station and so on so
they're going to call this allocate
instead of issue and to confuse the
exhibit of even further some call the
issue part dispatch so we dispatch the
instruction to reservation stations and
the aerobie entries similarly what we
have been calling dispatch some will
call execute some will call it issue so
we issued the instruction from a
reservation station to execution as well
as a residual dispatch which is we
dispatch the instruction to execution
and finally the comment is most often
called commit but sometimes it's been
called complete which introduces some
confusion because actually the
instruction completes execution well
before it commits it's just that now the
term complete would refer to commit if
that's the nomenclature that they're
using and then commit is also often
called retire so we retire the
instruction from the processor and
because a lot of papers have been
written by academics especially graduate
students commit has also been called
graduate you can guess why